# Matthew Ramirez

## Full Stack Developer

## Contact Info:

(858)-256-6180 Gmail LinkedIn Github Portfolio Site (WIP)

San Diego, CA (Remote)

## Summary:

Full stack developer backed with ten years of strong communication and team building skills developed through the food service industry. Motivated to bring accountability and efficiency that creates a unique experience in design and web development. Creative problem solving grants the ability to complete software testing and debugging with enthusiasm and motivation.

## Technical Skills:

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HAML, HTML, CSS, Frameworks: React, Ruby on Rails

Databases: PostgreSQL, Active Record TTD/Other. Jest, RSpec, Git/Version Control, Postman

## Experience:

#### Notch8 - Web Application Development Company

San Diego, CA | Feb 5th, 2021-Present

- Interned and adapted working in a real world Agile development setting from established engineers and designers.
- Facilitated stand-ups and integrated changes on code base that resolved set Kanban issues as a systematized Scrum team.

#### LEARN Academy - Web Developer Bootcamp

San Diego, CA | Nov 2nd, 2020-Feb 5th, 2021

- Completed organized Full Stack training integrating real life programming with hands-on problem solving.
- Experienced 480+ hours of intensive web development education including actively involved pair/ mob programming.
- Invested proficiency in JavaScript, React, Ruby and Rails, practiced test-driven development using Jest and RSpec, and created Full Stack Applications with a PostgreSQL database.

2010-2020 | Various Food Service Industry Companies | Bartending, Serving, Catering, Expo, Bar-Back Two positions listed below, look to LinkedIn for full work history.

#### Coronado Brewing Company Tasting Room - Lead Bartender

Bay Park, San Diego, CA | 2018-2020

- Coordinated quick thinking and team based knowledge to benefit the team and company as a whole.
- Encouraged knowledge in communication while problem solving quickly and understanding needs of others.
- Administered and executed plans with expertise during Covid lockdowns with General Manager.

#### Georges at the Cove - Expo, Bar-back

La Jolla, CA | 2016-2019

- Expedited precision thinking and focus in a high stress environment to produce above standard quality in product.
- Motivated leadership and coordination skills to stay directed on the team and companies established goals.
- Promoted and familiarized quickly with job duties to give the ability to assist in any situation.

### Education:

Crafton Hills College, Yucaipa, CA | 2014-2016 - Analyzed Public Speaking, Geology, and Yoga

Yucaipa High School, Yucaipa, CA | 2008-2011 - Achieved High School Diploma, conceptualized Video Production.